字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
为了阻止邪恶极速者萨维塔
In an attempt to stop the evil speedster Savitar,
我不小心闯入了未来
I was accidentally thrust into the future,
看到他杀死了我心爱的女人
and I saw him murder the woman that I love.
但是我不会再让这事发生了
But I won't let that happen.
我会尽我一切的努力来改变未来
I'm gonna do everything in my power to change the future,
而我是唯一来得及拯救她的人
and I'm the only one fast enough to keep her alive.
我就是  闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously, on "The Flash"...
萨维塔杀了你的那晚
The night that Savitar kills you,
你手上没有带戒指
you didn't have a ring on your finger.
我们还没订婚
We weren't engaged yet.
你就想如果我们订婚了
So you thought that if we were...
就可能改变未来
That it might change the future.
我们的一部分总会是有污点的
Now there's always gonna be a part of us that's tainted.
萨维塔为什么要藏在神速力里
Why is Savitar hiding in the Speed Force?
那就是你未来把他困住的地方
That's where the future you trapped him.
没错
That's right.
我有逃出地狱的东西  华莱士
I have what I need to escape my hell, Wallace.
不是所有  我们还有魔法石的一部分
Not everything. We still have a piece of that stone.
不见了
It's gone?
如果萨维塔拿到完整的魔法石
If Savitar gets ahold of the stone...
他一定会逃出去
He'll escape for sure.
你无法毁掉魔法石  华莱士
You can't get rid of that stone, Wallace.
你的速度还不够快  无法靠自己把它扔进
You're not fast enough to throw it into the Speed Force
神速力里
by yourself.
沃利取代了我在神速力中的位置
Wally has taken my place in the Speed Force.
我们必须把他救回来  我们必须得去救他
We have to bring him back. We have to save him.
我的恐惧是造成这一切的根源
My fear is the reason for all of this.
萨维塔说得对  这都是因为我
Savitar was right. This is all because of me,
因为我的软弱
because of my weakness.
闪点
Flashpoint.
因为这事  所有人的人生都改变了
And because of it, everyone's lives have changed.
我所爱的人都在受折磨
Everyone I love is suffering.
不能这样下去了
This has to stop.
不能再因为我让别人受到伤害了
I can't let anyone hurt anymore because of me.
他们不应该为我的错而受惩罚
No one else should have to pay for my sins.
他们不会了
And they won't.
再也不会了
Ever again.
西斯科
Cisco.
把缺口房间准备好
Get the Breach Room ready.
好的  你要做什么
Okay, for what?
我要去救沃利
I'm gonna save Wally.
你要怎么做
How exactly are you going to do that?
我要再回到神速力里
I'm going back into the Speed Force.
闪电侠
第三季
第十六集
我一直在想象
I'm just trying to wrap my mind around
你再次进到神速力里的情形
you going into the Speed Force again.
萨维塔说他在里面待了好几年了
The Savitar said he was there for years.
你说那里就像太空一样
You said it was like being in space.
-我知道  -那你打算怎么做呢
- I know. - So what are you gonna do?
你就在里面跑来跑去  直到找到他吗
You gonna run in there and run around till you find him?
-那永远没有尽头  -我知道
- It's endless. - I know.
但这是救沃利唯一的办法
And this is the only way to save Wally.
是是  我知道  可我们需要定个计划
Yeah, yeah, I just-- we need a plan.
我
I--I...
我不想再失去一个儿子了
I don't wanna lose both my sons.
各位  我对神速力不太理解
Look, gang, I don't understand the Speed Force,
可是这里有很多人对它很了解
but there are plenty of people in this room who do.
我觉得你又有什么高见了
Am I correct in assuming there's a point coming?
我的高见就是你为什么不能利用你的才学
My point is why can't you use your knowledge to fashion
为年轻的BA设计一种安全措施  这样
some kind of safety precaution for young BA right here so that,
当他身处在神速力时  就不会迷失方向了
while he's in the Speed Force, he doesn't get lost.
所以你是说我只要
Oh, so you're saying I can just whip up
打开一个维度范围
some kind of inter-dimensional tether
把他和这个宇宙牢牢地绑在一起
to just anchor him to the Universe?
没错
Yeah.
-我完全可以这么做  -没错
- That's exactly what I can do. - Yeah!
我们要用氦来做饭了
Now we're cooking with helium.
没错  我可以添加一个生物成分
Yes, and I can-- I can add a biological component
用来测量他在神速力里的生命体征
that will measure his vitals when he's in the Speed Force.
-这个主意不错  -谢谢你  凯特琳
- That's a great idea. - Thank you, Caitlin.
因为如果我们能检测巴里的生命体征
Because if we can monitor Barry's vitals,
一有不稳定  我们立刻会知道
we'll know if they fluctuate,
就能把他拉回来了
and we can pull him out.
你是说把我们俩拉回来
You mean "Pull us out."
没错  如果你要去救沃利  我也要去
Yeah, if you're going in there to save Wally, so am I.
杰西  你要留在这
Jesse, you're gonna stay here.
因为如果你爸发现
Because if your father finds out
你迷失在某个消极的世界里
you're lost in some negative world,
第一个要痛扁的人就是我
the first person to get a broken schnoz is me.
有消极世界吗
There's a negative world?
当然有消极世界
Yeah, negative world.
真的吗  地球29上有超级玛丽吗
Really? They have Super Mario on Earth-29?
有  还挑战我呢
Yeah, challenge me.
巴里  你需要我的帮忙  你的肩膀还伤着
Barry, you need my help. Your shoulder is still broken.
没事  快愈合了
It's okay. It's almost healed.
不  听着  我可以的
No, look, I can do this.
我知道  但是你要留在这
I know, but I need you to stay here.
我不在的时候  维护城市安全
Keep the city safe while I'm gone.
这件事我必须一个人去做
And this is something I have to do alone, okay?
好吧
Fine.
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧  开工吧
Okay, let's go to work.
我能和你说两句吗
Can I talk to you?
好
Yeah.
我会找到沃利的
I'm gonna find Wally.
无论他被关在哪
Whatever's holding him,
无论他为什么被困住
whatever's keeping him trapped in there,
我都会把他带回来的
I'm gonna get him back.
-好  -好的
- Okay. - Okay.
爱瑞丝
Iris...
我失去你了吗
Did I lose you?
巴仔
Bar.
怎么了
What's going on?
没事  没事  我只是尽量让她
Nothing, nothing, I'm just trying to make her
别这么担心
not worry so much.
担心沃利还是你
About Wally or you?
乔  现在不是说这个的时候
Joe, now's not the time, all right?
你将要冒着生命危险去救她弟弟
Look, you are about to risk your life  to save her brother.
我认为现在说最合适不过了
I think now is the perfect time.
她对我们之间存有疑虑
She's having doubts about us.
对嫁给我存有疑虑
About marrying me.
她取消订婚了吗
Did she call off the engagement?
看来我把未来改变得太多了
Guess I changed the future one too many times.
这样应该就行了
I think that's gonna do it.
我们应该能用这个监控巴里的生命体征
We should be able to use this to keep track of Barry's vitals.
他是航员  我们就是休斯顿宇航中心
He'll play astronaut, and we'll play Houston.
没错  但是他在神速力里时
Right, but how exactly are you gonna track his location
你要怎么追踪他的位置
when he's in the Speed Force?
在我们上次用来把巴里拉回来的东西上
Well, this is just a simple modification
做一个简单的改动就行了
from what we used to get Barry out last time,
那个电极头环
so the electrode halo?
-上次朱利安还没加入我们的小队  -还没
- Julian wasn't part of the team last time. - Not yet.
对  那个我们用来和萨维塔对话的东西
Right. You know that thing we used to talk to Savitar?
-对  -那就是电极头环
- Yes. - Meet the electrode halo.
我和头环之间就是通过金牙并利用电磁
So basically these two are linked electromagnetically
而相互连接
via Goldtooth.
金牙
Goldtooth?
没错  西斯科·拉蒙发明的
Yeah, it's kind of the Cisco Ramon
一种跨维度版本的蓝牙
interdimensional equivalent of Bluetooth.
我挺得意的
Kind of proud of it.
总之  无论巴里被困在多元宇宙的哪个角落
Anyway, it gives us all the relevant locus information
这东西都能给我们确切的位置信息
no matter what corner of the multiverse Barry's stuck in.
如果巴里需要我们的帮助
And, if Barry needs our help,
它就会刺激西斯科的前额皮质
it'll stimulate Cisco's prefrontal cortex.
然后我会打开缺口  送他回来
And I'll open a breach and... send him back in.
好极了  多元宇宙  缺口  头环
Good Lord, multiverses, breaches, halos,
真是小菜一碟
easy bloody peasy.
没错  我觉得他已经懂了
By George, I think he's got it.
西斯科  你准备好了吗
Cisco, you about ready?
时刻准备着
Born ready.
好吧  碰碰运气吧
Okay. Here's winging it.
碰碰运气  什么意思
Winging it? Wait, what do you mean?
意思是  我其实没有神速力的地图
Well, I mean, I don't really have a map of the Speed Force,
我用震波送巴里进去时
so when I vibe Barry into it...
你不知道我会去哪里
You have no idea where I'm gonna land.
但好在  如果他被困在
But the good news is, if he gets stuck
那一边的某个地方  我们能把他找回来
on the wrong side of the tracks, now we can fish him out.
找到我的孩子
Find my boy.
我会竭尽所能
I'm gonna do whatever it takes.
谢谢
Thank you.
我爱你  爱瑞丝
I love you, Iris.
我也爱你
I love you too.
准备好了吗
Are we ready?
可以出发了
Good to go.
前往无穷无尽的世界
To infinity and beyond.
我一放开你  就全靠你自己了
Okay, once I let go, you're on your own.
放手吧
Do it.
祝你好运
Good luck.
沃利
Wally?
有人吗
Hello?
你好  巴仔
Hey, Bar.
中城警局
你怎么在这儿
Why are you here?
你为什么回来这地方
Why did you come back to this place?
我来救沃利·韦斯特
I'm here to save Wally West.
总是逞英雄啊  巴里
Ever the hero, huh, Barry?
他被困在这里都怪我
It's my fault that he's trapped here.
是吗
Is it?
沃利·韦斯特人呢
Where is Wally West?
可以说他其实不在这儿
He's not exactly here, per se.
他在你创造的监狱里
He's in the prison you created.
未来的你创造的
Well, your future self, that is.
我怎么救他出来
How do I get him out?
我觉得你会发现
I think you'll find we're not gonna be
我们没有上次你来时那么通融了
as accommodating as we were the last time you visited us.
这话究竟什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
意思是时过境迁了
It means things have changed.
我们把极速还给你是因为你答应
We gave you your speed back because you said you'd
甘心忍受你母亲的死
come to terms with your mother's death,
但你骗了我们
but you lied to us.
-我  -你回到过去
- I-- - You went back in time
救了她
and saved her.
因为如此  你创造了闪点
And, in doing so, you created Flashpoint.
极速那时刚杀了我父亲
Zoom had just killed my father.
我们知道  我们明白
We know, and we understand,
所以我们放任你那么做
which is why we allowed you to do that,
但有因必有果
but choices have consequences.
恐怕我们不能再让你种下那样的因
And I'm afraid we can't let you make any more choices like that.
沃利还只是个孩子
Wally is just a kid.
他也是闪电侠
He's a Flash.
他自己做出了选择
He made his choice.
如今他需要承担后果  正如你一样
Now he has to live with it, just like you do.
放走沃利之前我哪里也不去
I'm not going anywhere until Wally's free.
那你就做好永远在这里的准备吧
Then be prepared to spend an eternity in here.
你怎么点了单倍浓咖啡
Why would you order a single espresso?
至少要双倍的
It's gotta be at least a double espresso.
我三倍特浓也可以
I can go triple.
-对我完全没影响  -可怕
- Doesn't affect me at all. - Frightening.
我可以喝四倍  六倍都行
I can have a quadruple, a sextuple.
你来了  我给大家买咖啡去
There you are. I'm gonna get us all coffees
我们有好多事情要做
'cause we got a lot of work to do, you know?
好多  好多事情要做
A lot of-- A lot of stuff to do.
对我毫无影响  对我毫无影响
It doesn't affect me though. It doesn't affect me at all!
好吧
Okay.
他吓到我了
He scares me.
我在想  你觉得我们能不能用这个
I was wondering, do you think you could use this
追踪萨维塔的位置
to track Savitar's location?
这个主意倒不错
That's not a bad idea.
之前我没法这样做
You know, I couldn't before because he was
因为他在神速力里  但现在他出来了
in the Speed Force, but, now that he's out of it,
无拘无束自由自在了  我相信
feeling footloose and fancy-free, I'm sure--
抱歉  我真是太迟钝了
I'm sorry, you know what? That was insensitive of me.
没事
It's fine.
如果我现在找到了萨维塔
Okay, so let's say I find Savitar, right now.
你要怎么办
What are you gonna do about it?
我要去抓他
I'm gonna go after him.
杰西  你疯了吗
Jesse, are you out of your mind?
我没疯  我不能就坐在这里等
No, okay? I can't just sit here waiting.
怎么不能  你必须等
You can, and you will.
我们必须等  而且很快
We all will. And, soon enough, Barry's
巴里就会带着沃利逃出神速力的
gonna get Wally out of the Speed Force.
你并不能确定
You don't know that, okay?
我们什么都不能确定
We don't know anything.
我们唯一能确定的是萨维塔出来了
The only thing we actually know is that Savitar is out there,
如果我们可以  我们必须找到他
and, if we can, we have to find him
把他送回原来他呆的地方去
and send him right back where he came from.
你要留下来
You're staying here.
闪电侠消失于危机中
爱瑞丝
Iris.
朱莉·格瑞尔
2024年4月25日
是我写了那篇文章
I wrote that article.
署名以前是我的  但现在不是了
That used to be my byline, but not anymore.
2024年还早
Well, 2024 is a long ways away.
未来还可能会改变
Things could still change.
如果一切都太晚了呢
What if it's too late?
如果有些事发生了就不能抹去呢
What if some things can't be undone?
你是后悔了吗
You having second thoughts?
我想我只是担心我做了错误的决定
I guess I'm just worried that I made the wrong decision.
怎么
And what?
你觉得暂停订婚的事才会让巴里
You think that calling things off sent Barry
跑进神速力去吗
running into the Speed Force?
别这样  我们都明白无论怎样
Please, we both know that he was gonna
他都会去救沃利的
go save Wally no matter what.
是啊  他就是那样的英雄
Yeah, that's just the kind of hero he is.
宝贝  我知道你的感受
Sweetheart, I know-- I know how you're feeling.
你现在无法辨别怎么做才是对的
You can't figure out which way's up right now, can you?
帮你自己个忙
Do yourself a favor.
去审视一下你那博大美丽的心灵
Look deep inside that big, beautiful heart of yours.
你会找到你想要的答案的
You'll find the answer you're looking for.
艾迪·斯旺的生活本可以不同的
Eddie Thawne's life was almost so different.
爱瑞丝本要做他的妻子
Iris was about to be his wife.
乔本要成为他的岳父
Joe was about to be his father-in-law.
但是事情没有那么发展下去对不对  巴里
But things didn't turn out that way, did they, Barry?
他没有过上那样的人生
Instead of that life being his legacy...
这个才是
This is.
这么说你回来就只是为了救沃利
So the only reason you came back is to save Wally.
是的
Yes.
没别的原因了吗
There's no other reason?
没了
No.
那么好吧  巴仔
All right then, Bar.
你想救沃利  只需要穿过这些门
If you want Wally, all you need to do is go through those doors.
但你先得超过那个东西的速度
But you're gonna have to outrun that thing first.
时间亡灵
Time Wraith.
*别哭  小宝贝  别出声*
*Hush, little baby, don't say a word*
*妈妈要给你买一只知更鸟*
*Mama's gonna buy you a mockingbird*
凯特琳
Caitlin.
*要是知更鸟不唱歌*
*And if that mockingbird don't sing*
*妈妈就给你买个钻石戒指*
*Mama's gonna buy you a diamond ring*
那个孩子...
That baby...
她...
Is she...
漂亮吗
Beautiful.
真像她母亲
Just like her mother.
罗尼
Ronnie.
你好  巴里
Hello, Barry.
我们得聊聊
We need to talk.
也许有什么和拉廷格液体类似的新型金属
Perhaps some sort of new metal akin to a Luttinger liquid?
你有什么想法
What do you think?
我不知道这是什么玩意
Man, I don't know what this is.
我只知道  这是印度教极速之神盔甲的碎片
All I know, it just came off the armor of some hindu speed god, so...
这就像魔法石被扔进的盒子
It's like the box the philosopher's stone came in.
既存在又不存在
It simultaneously exists and doesn't exist.
就和薛罗谔的猫一样  还记得薛罗谔吗
Like Schroeder's cat. Remember Schroeder?
那个人把猫放在一个盒子里
Guy with the cat in the box
这只猫同时又是死的又是活的  顺便说下
both dead and alive at the same time, dun, dun, dun, which, by the way,
这似乎有一半时间对动物很残忍
seems like cruelty for animals half the time.
好吧  我觉得你说的是薛定谔吧
Okay, I think you're thinking of Schrodinger, maybe?
薛定...  不
Schroding--no.
对  因为薛罗谔是《史努比花生大电影》里的人
Yeah, 'cause Schroeder's the guys from "Peanuts."
-才不是呢  -是的  那个弹钢琴的人
- I don't think so. - Yeah, the one with the piano.
弹...  查理·布朗有我们地球上的钢琴
The-- Charlie Brown has the piano on my Earth.
这就是个笑话  因为他根本不会弹钢琴
That's the whole gag 'cause he can't play the piano.
-他太烂了  -不对
- He's terrible. - No.
老天  谁要管猫还有钢琴
Oh, my God, who cares about cats or pianos
还是什么可怕的"花生"
or the freaking "Peanuts"?
不是"那个花生"
It's not "The Peanuts."
就是《史努比花生大电影》
It's just "Peanuts."
你们研究这个东西很久了
You have been studying this thing for hours.
我们到底能不能用它追踪萨维塔
Can we or can we not use it to track Savitar?
好了  好了  言归正传
Okay, all right, wind it in.
据我们所知  这个碎片
As far as we can tell, the shard is made
由接近零阻力的材料制成
of near-frictionless material
状态不停地变化
that's in a constant state of flux.
所以它表面上是完全静止的
So while it's utterly motionless on the outside --
内部却在不断运动
It's constantly moving on the inside.
是的  就好像
Yes, it's as if it's being
有什么外力在影响它
affected by some sort of external source,
这跟潮汐力受月相影响大抵相同
much like the tides are affected by the phases of the moon.
好  好吧  那肯定是萨维塔
Okay, okay, then it has to be Savitar.
这是他的盔甲上掉下来的
I mean, this was part of his armor.
也许它想和其它部分重连
Maybe it's trying to reconnect with its other pieces.
对了
That's it.
这就像"铁巨人"
It's just like "The Iron Giant."
如果是这样  这个碎片就能带我们找到他
If this is true, then this shard could lead us right to him.
这是一个思路
That's an idea.
好  那我们还等什么
Okay, all right, so what are we waiting for?
我们...
Let's--
别着急  杰西·快客
Hold your roll, Jesse Quick.
我代表大家说说  你心中的犹豫
This hesitation that you feel, on behalf of the group,
让我们意识到一开始
is our realization that this "Go for broke" attitude
正是"孤注一掷"的态度让华莱士
is the very attitude that got Wallace in his predicament
陷入困境  对吗
in the first place. Am I right?
无法相信我会说出这话
I can't believe I'm uttering the words,
-但我其实赞同HR  -同上
- but I actually agree with H.R. - Ditto.
-谢了  伙计们  -单凭一个极速者
- Thanks, boys. - A lone speedster...
根本不是萨维塔的对手
It's just no match for Savitar.
-对  但是  -杰西  我们会找到他的
- Yeah, but-- - Jesse, we're gonna find him.
什么时候
When?
真正的闪电侠回来的时候
When the real Flash gets back.
我不该这么说
That came out wrong, um...
我说错话了
Put my foot in it.
杰西  杰西
Jesse, Jesse!
杰西  杰西  快问快答
Oh, Jesse, hey, Jesse, quick question:
墨尔乐还是解百纳葡萄酒
Merlot or Cabernet?
什么
What?
你觉得一个穿11码鞋的大个子老头
What wine do you think would go best with a big, old
最适合喝哪种葡萄酒
men's size 11 shoe stuffed in his mouth?
-HR  -怎么了
- H.R.? - Yeah?
-我想静静  -我懂  我懂
- Just leave me alone. - I get it, I get it.
我懂  萨维塔
I get-- Savitar--
萨维塔伤害了你爱的人  你想以牙还牙
Savitar hurt the one you love, now you wanna hurt Savitar.
对  猜对了  我想
Yeah, bet your ass, I do.
不  我懂  我很欣赏
No, I get it. I--I love it.
我也尊重这点  但我有点担心
I respect it. I'm a little worried though
你报仇心切  最后受伤的
that, in your zeal for payback, you might be the one
可能是你
who ends up getting hurt.
-在我的地球  -对
- On my Earth... - Yeah.
-我就是真正的闪电侠  -我知道
- I am the real Flash. - I know.
所以我
That's why I--
我才说了那番话
I should've said what I said.
不不  你不该  好吗
No, no, you shouldn't have, okay?
因为我之前打败了很多怪物
'Cause I've fought plenty of monsters before.
对  没错
Yeah, absolutely.
但打败过萨维塔吗
Like Savitar, though?
因为  听着  是这样的
'Cause, look, here's the thing.
要是你父亲在这  他会
If your father were here, he would--
竭尽全力阻止萨维塔
Do everything in his power to stop Savitar.
而我也正要那么做
And that is exactly what I'm gonna do.
好好
Okay, okay.
向你致敬  你可真是"老顽固"哈里的
I mean, hats off to you. You really are Hard-Hat Harry's
-女儿啊  -对  没错
- little girl, aren't you? - Yeah, I am,
而你不是他
and you're not him.
那就别为难彼此  别费劲了
So just do us both a favor and stop trying to be.
这让你心烦
This troubles you.
本该诞生却从未存在过的另一个生命
Another life that could've been and never was.
凯特琳和罗尼本该拥有的
Caitlin and Ronnie should've had that.
拥有家庭和未来
A family, a future.
未来不总是如我们所愿
The future doesn't always turn out as we want it to.
我知道你在做什么
I see what you're doing.
先是艾迪  现在是罗尼  让我看到所有
First Eddie, now Ronnie, showing me all of the people
为更伟大的事业牺牲的人
who sacrificed themselves for the greater good.
不  巴里  他们为你而牺牲
No, Barry, their sacrifices were for you,
沃利尝试阻止萨维塔时也是如此
as was Wally's when he attempted to stop Savitar.
不  沃利被萨维塔骗了
No, Savitar tricked Wally.
现在他被困了
And now he's trapped.
沃利不属于神速力
Wally doesn't belong in the Speed Force.
你得让我代替他
You have to let me take his place.
所以我才来这
And that's why I'm here.
或是另有目的  巴里
Or the other reason, Barry.
我想为沃利牺牲自己
I wanna sacrifice myself for Wally.
-我们不会允许的  -为什么
- We can't allow that. - Why not?
因为沃利的下场全得他独自承受
Because where Wally's gone is a hell all his own.
萨维塔说过"有人会遭遇比死更惨的命运"
Savitar said, "One will suffer a fate far worse than death."
这话说的不是你
And it's not for you.
走吧  巴里  现在为时未晚
Leave, Barry, while you still can.
不
No.
不管沃利被困在哪儿
Whatever hell Wally's trapped in,
我都要救他出来
I'm gonna set him free,
救不出来  我就不走
and I'm not leaving here until I do.
很好  警告过你了
Very well, but you were warned.
亨特·佐勒蒙
Hunter Zolomon.
快点
Come on, come on.
-是巴里吗  -有什么情况吗
- Is it Barry? - Did something happen to him?
不知道  一秒前  遥感数据还
We don't know. One second, the telemetry
十分正常  然后...
was perfectly normal, and--
他的生命体征开始急速下降
Then his vitals, they just started crashing.
我们警告过你
We warned you.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
你说要牺牲自己  但你还是让别人
You speak of sacrifice, yet you still let others
替你扛肩上的重任
bear the burdens that should be on your shoulders.
好吧  你说得对
Okay, okay, you're right.
你说得对
You're right.
我不该让沃利去救爱瑞丝
I never should've asked Wally to save Iris.
那是我该做的
It should've been me.
求你  让我救他
Please, let me save him.
从永恒的折磨中解救沃利·韦斯特
There's only one way to free Wally West
只有一个方法
from his eternal torment.
你先得解救自己
You must free yourself first.
我爱你  爱瑞丝
I love you, Iris.
不
No.
-西斯科  他...  -我不知道
- Cisco, is he-- - I don't know, I don't know.
找出来
Find out!
找不到
I can't.
-连接中断了  -什么
- The tether's gone. - What?
那是他和沃利逃出神速力的救命线
That was him and Wally's lifeline out of the Speed Force.
我们怎么把他们救回来呢
How are we gonna get them back?
据我所知  不能
I don't know that we can.
有人吗
Hello?
沃利
Wally?
沃利  沃利
Wally, Wally!
我要把你救出来
I'm gonna get you out, okay?
再坚持一下
Just hang on.
探视时间结束  闪电侠
Visiting hours are over, Flash.
所以...
So...
那不是你的
That's not yours.
-让开  -不行
- Get out of my way. - I can't do that.
你不能用那东西去对付萨维塔
Not if you're planning on using that to fight Savitar.
我不允许
I can't.
你说服不了我的
You're not gonna talk me out of this, okay?
-我告诉过你  你不是...  -不是你爸
- I already told you you're not-- - Not your dad.
清清楚楚地听到了
That message was received loud and clear.
现在听我说
Now hear mine.
一个人去找萨维塔
Taking on Savitar all alone
救不回华莱士  杰西
is not gonna bring Wallace back, Jesse.
只会害死自己  那样不行的
It's just gonna get you killed, and that,
朋友  那样不行的
my friend, that is not happening.
我不允许
Not on my watch.
说完了吗
You done?
说完了
Yeah, said my piece.
猜怎么着
And guess what?
我还是没...
I'm still not--
动...
Moving...
莫名其妙地爽呢
That was oddly satisfying.
他怎么了
What's happening to him?
沃利·韦斯特被困在无尽的时间循环里
Wally West is caught in an endless temporal loop,
就像你将来把萨维塔困在这里的样子
just like Savitar after you imprisoned him here in the future.
怪不得他恨你
No wonder he hates you.
他看见了什么
What's he seeing?
他在不断重复人生中最痛苦的时刻
He's reliving the single most painful moment of his life
反反复复
over and over again.
看见她母亲的死亡
His mother's death.
沃利
Wally.
不该由他承受
He doesn't deserve this.
那我猜猜  该是你吗
Let me guess. You do?
我知道我的地狱是什么
I know what my hell is.
我已经在未来看到了
I've already seen it in the future.
你不喜欢未来的样子吧  闪电侠
You don't like the future, Flash?
-改变它  -我做不到
- Change it. - I can't.
你听不懂吗  我做不到
Don't you get it? I can't!
我不够快  而他可以
I'm not fast enough. He is.
那就是为什么应该让我代替他
That's why you have to let me take his place.
沃利可以救爱瑞丝
Wally can save Iris.
你还是没明白  巴里
Not learning your lesson, Barry.
你总是说一套  做一套
You keep telling us one thing and then doing another.
你知道为什么莱昂纳多·史纳特
You wanna know what inspired Leonard Snart
会自我牺牲吗
to sacrifice himself?
是因为你  巴里·艾伦
It was you, Barry Allen.
是你启发他变得更好
You inspired him to be better.
你让他变得无私  为了别人牺牲自己
You inspired him to be selfless, to sacrifice himself for others,
像你一样做个英雄
to be a hero, just like you.
我不是英雄  最近不是了
I'm no hero. Not lately.
所以呢
So what?
你撑不住了吗  红衣极速者
You've had enough, Scarlet Speedster?
准备挂起战衣  放弃一切了吗
Time to hang up the cowl and give it all up?
你一旦放弃
Well, if you're out...
就出局了
you're out.
我不想再战斗了
I'm done fighting.
我们知道  而且那就是问题所在
We know, and that's exactly the problem.
你以为看见爱瑞丝的死就是最惨的事
You think seeing Iris' death is hell?
你还没见识到全部
You ain't seen nothing yet.
我们快离开这里
Let's get you out of here.
你这个破金属片
All right, you stupid piece of metal,
带我去找你的主人
take me to your leader.
找到了
Gotcha.
杰西·快客
Jesse Quick.
我就知道你会来找我
I knew you would come for me.
你怎么知道我会来这里
How'd you know I was coming here?
我知道所有正在发生的事
Because I know everything that happens.
我已经经历过了
I've already lived it.
我不怕你
I'm not afraid of you.
你应该怕
You should be.
杰西
Jesse.
HR
H.R.?
现在想说服我有点迟了
It's a little late to talk me out of this, okay?
我并不想说服你什么
I'm not gonna try and talk you out of anything.
我吸取教训了
I learned that lesson.
你拿了属于我的东西
You have something that belongs to me.
我需要点帮助  HR
I need a little help here, H.R.
我正在想办法
Bum, bum, thinking.
快点想
Think faster.
有什么线索呢  我们对抗的是萨维塔
What do we got? We're fighting Savitar.
萨维塔是极速之神  他无所不能
Savitar is a speed god. He's omnipotent.
无懈可击
He's invulnerable.
那他为什么要穿盔甲
Then why does he need a suit of armor?
杰西  他的弱点
Jesse, he's vulnerable
在盔甲下面  找个缝隙  找道口子
somewhere under the suit. Find a gap, find an opening,
放手一搏
and go for it.
杰西·快客  我已经安排好你的未来了
I have such plans for you in the future, Jesse Quick.
我也安排好你的了
And I have plans for you too.
这是为了沃利
This is for Wally.
杰伊
Jay.
什么事
Yeah?
真的是你吗  还是说
Is this really you, or is this
这只是神速力的又一个测试
just another Speed Force test?
是的  孩子  真的是我
Yeah, kid, it's really me.
你是怎么过来的
How?
团队和你失联之后
As soon as the team lost contact with you,
西斯科就立刻来到了我的地球告知了我详情
Cisco came to my Earth and told me what was happening.
我是过来帮你的
I came here to help.
我们去救沃利吧
Let's get Wally.
恐怕我不能让你这么做
'Fraid I can't let you do that.
动作没你巅峰时期那么快了啊  加里克
Getting a little slow in your golden age there, Garrick.
住手
Stop.
这个同样办不到
Can't do that either.
够了
Enough!
我要带沃利走
I'm taking Wally.
我们不能让你这么做  巴里
We can't let you do that, Barry.
真的吗  那就试试阻止我
Yeah? Try and stop me.
沃利
Wally?
Wally.
巴里  杰伊
Barry, Jay.
我看到我妈妈了
I saw my mom.
-我知道  我知道  -我妈妈
- I know, I know. - My mom.
我知道  现在看着我  好吗
I know. Look at me now, okay?
一切都结束了
It's over.
你现在自由了
You're free now,
听到了吗  我们现在回家  好吗
okay? We're going home, all right?
没事了  我们回家
It's okay. We're going home.
杰伊  我们走吧
Jay, let's go.
抱歉  孩子  我要在这待一段时间了
Sorry, kid, this is where I stay for a while.
什么  你在说什么啊
What? What are you talking about?
我们都清楚需要有一位极速者替代沃利的位置
We both know that a speedster needs to take Wally's place.
这就是我过来的原因
That's why I'm here.
不  不  杰伊  你被极速囚禁的时候
No, no, Jay, you already lived your hell
已经受过这种地狱般的折磨了
when you were Zoom's prisoner.
而你让我重获自由  我欠你一份情
And you set me free, and I owe you for that.
-杰伊  -我已经跑过一次美妙的赛程了
- Jay-- - I've run a hell of a race,
但每场马拉松都是有终点的
but every marathon has a finish line.
现在终于到了我冲线的时刻了  而你
Time's finally come for me to cross it, but you--
你  巴里  得永远地终结这一切
you, Barry, need to put an end to this once and for all
并阻止萨维塔
and stop Savitar.
如何阻止
How?
做你最擅长的事
Do what you do best.
做闪电侠
Be The Flash.
西斯科说他可以用这个追踪你们的位置
Cisco said that he could use this to track you
并把你们接回去
and bring you home.
等我回来把你从这救出去
I'm gonna get this back to you again
一定把这个还给你
when I break you out of here.
回头见了  闪电侠
See you soon, Flash.
什么情况
What's happening?
你觉得你能把他们钩回来吗
Do you think you can reel them in?
我不知道  我从未感受过如此强大的
I don't know. I've never felt this much
震波反馈
harmonic feedback.
就好像神速力要
It feels like the Speed Force is about to--
-沃利  -巴里
- Wally! - Barry!
天哪
Oh, my God.
你们还好吗
Are you okay?
我们会好的
We will be.
等等
Hold on a second.
进去了三位极速者  却只出来了两位
Three speedsters go in, and only two come out.
杰伊
Jay...
杰伊为了救沃利
Jay stayed back
留在了那里
to save Wally.
来吧  沃利  我们给你检查一下
Come on, Wally, let's get you checked out.
我以为我要失去我的两个儿子了
I thought I lost both my boys.
谢谢你把他救了回来
Thanks for bringing him back.
不用谢
You're welcome.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我以为我也要失去你了
I thought I'd lost you too.
我哪也不去
I'm right here.
神速力
The Speed Force.
就那么以艾迪·斯旺之形在你面前显现吗
And it just appeared to you in the form of Eddie Thawne?
-还有罗尼  -史纳特
- And Ronnie? - And Snart.
所有这些让我明白了一件事
All to teach me another lesson.
什么
Which was what?
拯救爱瑞丝是我的使命
Saving Iris is my responsibility
是我一人的
and mine alone.
这也就是为什么神速力不让我代替沃利
It's why the Speed Force didn't let me take Wally's place,
而杰伊会牺牲自己去做
why Jay sacrificed himself to do it.
好让我能完成这事
So I could finish this.
杰伊是当之无愧的英雄
Jay, hero among heroes.
是啊
Yeah.
我们不能就这么把他留在那里
We can't just leave him in there.
不会的
We won't.
我会打败萨维塔  我们一起解救他
I'll beat Savitar. We'll get him out.
那就好  对我来说
Good, 'cause it seems to me the Speed Force
神速力实在是个疯狂的地方
is a little bit of a crazy place.
华莱士知道
Just ask Wallace.
是  没错  沃利所目睹的
Yeah, yeah, what-- what Wally saw--
会困扰他好一阵
it's gonna haunt him for a while.
所以  在他能彻底放下
So until he can get past it, and he's really ready
并且准备好回归前
to go back out there, Kid Flash is
闪电小子得有一阵不会出现了
gonna need to take a break for a while.
你还好吗
You okay?
你好吗
Are you?
是啊  你这还不算什么
Right, you should see the other guy.
凯特琳说我会好的
Caitlin said I'll be fine.
杰西  没想到你居然一个人去追萨维塔了
Jesse, I can't believe you went after Savitar by yourself.
你在想什么
What were you thinking?
如果是你  你也会这么做的
I mean, the same thing you were when you did it.
嗯  那是个错误
Yeah, that was a mistake.
我再也不会犯这样的错了
One that I will never make again.
是啊  我也不会
Yeah, yeah, me either.
至少在这个地球上不会
Not on this Earth, anyway.
等等  什么
Wait, what? You're going back
你就要回地球二了吗
to Earth-2 already?
-是地球三  -可是杰西  你才回来
- Earth-3, actually. - But you just got here, Jesse.
我知道的  我也想陪着你
I know, I know, and I want to be with you.
只是萨维塔说  他在未来对我有所安排
It's just Savitar said he had plans for me in the future.
我得阻止这样的情况发生
And I can't let that happen.
而且  在巴里把杰伊从神速力解救出来之前
Besides, until Barry can get Jay out of the Speed Force,
地球三得有个闪电侠守护
Earth-3 needs a Flash to protect it.
我爱你  杰西
I love you, Jesse.
我也爱你
I love you too.
地球三的恶棍准没好果子吃
You show those villains on Earth-3.
没人敢惹我们的杰西·快客
Nobody messes with our Jesse Quick.
没错  给他们点颜色看看
That's right. You give them hell.
你知道我会的
You know I will.
你需要我们的话  我们就在这
We're here if you need us, all right?
-一路顺风  -谢谢
- Safe travels. - Thanks.
很抱歉
Sorry for the, uh...
我也一样很抱歉  左勾拳练得不错
Yeah, yeah, me too. Good left-hook.
谢谢
Thanks.
我一点也不惊讶  我们威尔斯
I shouldn't be surprised. Us Wellses--
我们可不容小觑
We are forces to be reckoned with.
可不是吗
That we are.
谢谢你  HR
Thank you, H.R.
为什么
For what?
就为你是我的朋友
Just being a friend.
谢谢你
Thank you.
准备好了吗
You ready?
是的
Yeah.
这不是告别
This isn't good-bye.
对  这更像是回头见
No, it's more like "See you later."
等不及下次相见了
I can't wait.
那么
So,
我们无畏的杰西·快客在最近与
fun fact uncovered by our intrepid Jesse Quick,
所谓极速之神的争斗中揭开了有趣的真相
in her latest dust-up with the so-called "God of Speed,"
猜猜谁感觉到痛苦了
guess who feels pain.
你到底在说什么
What--what exactly are you saying?
你是说在那副盔甲之下他其实...
Are you saying that underneath the suit of armor that's he's--
没错  詹姆斯  他不是神
Yes, James. He's not a God.
他只是一介凡人
He's just a man, baby.
-凡人  -对
- A man? - Yeah.
谢谢你救了沃利
Thank you for saving Wally.
不客气
Of course.
我只是...
So, I just--
你告诉我你只想嫁给一个
Look, you told me that you only wanted to marry someone
真正爱你  而并不是
because they love you and not because
想要救你的人  我懂
they were trying to save you, and I get that.
我只是...
I just...
我经历过很多次生死
You know, I've lived with a lot of death,
生命中的悲剧
tragedy in my life,and
眼睁睁看着你死去...
seeing you die...
不为此备受折磨是不可能的
It's impossible not to be consumed by that.
我懂的
Yeah, no, I get that. I do.
只是...
It just...
你出于这种原因而向我求婚
it made me question if you were asking me
我觉得不太好  你懂吗
for the right reasons, you know?
是出于爱还是
If it was out of love or
责任感
responsibility.
但你离开之后
But, hey, look, while you were gone,
我意识到了一些事情
I realized something.
我不必质疑你想要娶我的原因
I don't have to doubt why you wanna marry me.
那和我想要嫁给你的原因是一样的
It's the same reason that I wanna marry you.
我想成为你的妻子  巴里
I wanna be your wife, Barry.
我爱你
I love you.
但...
But...
你是对的
you were right.
我向你求婚
I proposed
是因为我觉得那样可以救你
because I thought it would save you.
我以为沃利可以救你
I thought Wally would save you.
我错了
I--I was wrong.
我必须孤身一人在未来救下你  我会这么做
I alone have to save you in the future, and I'm going to,
但不是凭借改变现状
but not by changing it.
而是直面它
By embracing it.
好
Okay...
那是什么意思
what--what does that mean?
我的意思是...
It means that I--
我觉得我们
I think we need some space
需要分开一段时间
for a while.
抱歉
I'm sorry,
但我不知道继续这样
but--I--I don't-- I don't know how we can
我们该怎么过下去
move forward like this, with--
好的
Okay.
我回爸爸那儿去吧
I guess I'll go to my dad's.
不  你留在这里
No, you stay here.
我搬去西斯科那里
I'll--I'll stay with Cisco.